const questions = [
  {
    question: "Are you currently employed?",
    answer:
      "I am currently in between jobs and actively looking for a new opportunity.",

    color: "scarlet",
  },
  {
    question: "What appeals to you about web design?",
    answer:
      "What appeals to me most about web design is the ability to create something of use to someone else. That to me is so rewarding because not only do I get to use my abilities to create, but it’s utilized in a way to positively impact the experiences of other people.",

    color: "beige",
  },
  {
    question: "What was the best web design project you’ve worked on?",
    answer:
      "The Snap Still web app is probably the best web design project I’ve worked on thus far because my filmmaking buddies are able to use it for their film projects. Snap Still is a site, providing filmmakers and creatives alike with a platform to create mood boards during the planning phases of their projects. It allows users to be able to manage all of their boards in one place as well. The mocks were created in Figma, and the tech stack used includes React,Javascript, and CSS to style.",

    color: "green",
  },
  {
    question: "Do you specialize in any web design area?",
    answer:
      "In terms of specialization, I specialize in React and Javascript, but I am actively learning other sectors in web development to be well rounded within the field.",

    color: "white",
  },
  {
    question: "Can you explain what responsive web page design means?",
    answer:
      "Responsive design is basically an approach to web design that ensures web apps respond to differences in screen sizes appropriately. An example would be considering how a website would look on a tablet vs. a desktop screen vs a phone. The goal is to have that be a seamless experience for a user.",

    color: "yellow",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Imagine a client giving constructive criticism about your work. How would you respond?",
    answer:
      "I would respond positively. Ultimately my job is to be of service to the client. Along with that, constructive criticism is ultimately given to improve something, and I do not believe a person can truly grow in their profession without it. Growth and progression is always the goal for me. So if I am working for a client, and they have constructive criticism, I am all ears so that we can work together to accomplish the goal they have in mind.",

    color: "blue",
  },
  {
    question: "Can you describe how to optimize websites for speed?",
    answer:
      "There are a few ways that I am aware of how to optimize websites for speed. One way is code splitting. Code splitting is basically sending less code to the browser. This includes avoiding being repetitive , and using async loading,as it doesn’t require images, etc. to load only after the page has loaded. It also includes removing comments/ console.logs and unnecessary spaces in code.For React it can involve conditionally importing heavy code with React.lazy(). And also using dev tools to monitor web performance and make the necessary changes if needed in code.",

    color: "green",
  },
  {
    question:
      "How do you determine what color scheme to use in your web design?",
    answer:
      "In personal projects I go with colors that exude the theme/mood I’m aiming for. I am also sure to use colors that complement one another as well. Two sites I like to use to help with choosing color schemes are canva.com and coolors.co.",

    color: "purple",
  },
  {
    question: "What are your Favorite design tools to use?",
    answer:
      "For web design, my favorite design tools are Figma and Canva. Both allow me to design the full layout of the site in detail. Particularly, what I like about Figma is that I can share the project I am working on with someone, and they can see the unfinished version without either of us having to download anything. I also like that I, or a person who has access to the project can make comments on it as well. In Canva, I love how all of the graphic elements, and potential graphic elements I can use are in one space. They also have everything from tools aiding in color scheme, to having the ability to create animations to include in projects.",

    color: "scarlet",
  },
  {
    question: "Do you have experience producing UX designs?",
    answer:
      "I do have experience producing UX designs, as I’ve created designs in Figma and Adobe XD to turn into functional web apps.",

    color: "white",
  },
  {
    question: "What training courses developed your programming skills?",
    answer:
      "--The Scrimba Bootcamp/Front End Developer Career Path-- Udemy Complete Web development Boot Camp with Dr.Angela Yu-- Free Code Camp:Responsive Web Design,JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, Front End Development Library Certification, Data Visualization, Relational Database Certification.--The Odin Project--Youtube",

    color: "beige",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What experience do you have using HTTP and HTTP/2 in your design?",
    answer:
      "I've used Netlify and Github Pages to deploy sites,and HTTP and HTTP/2 is how data communicates on the web. It’s how data such as images, documents, videos,etc. are shared between the client and the server. It allows sites I have deployed to be accessed by users and how users are able to interact with them. I know HTTP/2 has improved performance as well.",

    color: "purple",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Will you be able to devote 30 to 40 hours of your time weekly for the company?",
    answer: "Yes.",

    color: "green",
  },
  {
    question:
      "How long would you expect to work for us if hired and how much will you request per hour if you are hired?",
    answer: "4 years and $48/hr",

    color: "yellow",
  },
  {
    question:
      "How do you stay current with the latest design trends, software developments, and technological tools?",
    answer:
      "I like to listen to the Scrimba podcast and attend their live workshops as well via youtube.I also checkout the Free Code Camp blog, and follow a good amount of developers on tik tok.",

    color: "blue",
  },
  {
    question: "Why are you the best web designer for this position?",
    answer:
      "I believe I’m best fit for the web designer position due to my knowledge, skills and experiences that directly align with the requirements and responsibilities of the role. Beyond my technical abilities, I enjoy working in collaborative environments with a team of people. I love the idea of contributing to something as well as having the opportunity to learn from those around me. My background in graphic design and filmmaking has often exposed me to collaborative projects, and working with a team to achieve a shared goal. While most of my coursework has predominantly focused on front-end applications, I am currently studying backend technologies through Free Code Camp to broaden my skill set, so that I’m able to contribute and in an effective way across the spectrum of web development. The field of web development is ever-changing and ever evolving, and that’s one of the things that I really like about it. My love for learning and trying my hand at new technologies keeps me curious and wanting to learn more about the industry.This is what allows me to stay up to date with the latest tech trends. In addition to this, in my experience of film editing and graphic design, I have worked with diverse visual and audio formats and made them compatible web formats. In summary, I strongly believe that my qualifications, skills, and experiences align well with the expectations of this role, and my passion for web design will make me an asset to the team.",

    color: "white",
  },
  {
    question: "Can you handle all these duties effectively?",
    answer:
      "Yes, I am confident that I can handle all of these duties effectively. Thank you for considering my candidacy and I look forward to the possibility of working together.",

    color: "scarlet",
  },
  {
    question: "Portfolio",
    portfolioLink: "https://ylexisb.github.io/mi-portfolio/",
    color: "beige",
  },
];
export default questions;
